utsystem.edu 2006-06-15

# The University of Texas System - Information Resources

> [The University of Texas System Administration](http://www.utsystem.edu/) maintains the U.T. System Administration web site as a public service. The following statement applies only to members of the general public and is intended to address concerns about the types of information gathered from the public and how that information is used. Employees of U.T. System Administration should refer to Business Procedures Memorandum 53-02-96, which outlines System Administration's internal policy for the use and protection of information resources.
> 
> Since U.T. System Administration is a public institution, the information we collect may be subject to public disclosure under the [Texas Public Information Act](http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/statutes/go/go0055200toc.html) ([Chapter 552](http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/statutes/go/go0055200toc.html) of the Texas Government Code). 
>
>>   
>  The U.T. TeleCampus collects somewhat different information from other servers within the U.T. System Administration site. You may view the [U.T. TeleCampus](http://www.telecampus.utsystem.edu/) privacy policy at: <http://tis.telecampus.utsystem.edu/tispp.asp>
>> 
>> ### I. Information Collected and Stored Automatically
>>
>>> **a. Cookies**
>>>
>>>> A "cookie" is a small file containing information that is placed on a user's computer by a web server. Typically, these files are used to enhance the user's experience of the site, to help users move between pages in a database, or to customize information for a user. U.T. System Administration servers do not store personally identifiable information in cookies from pages intended for use by the general public.  
>  Information stored in cookies by U.T. System Administration web servers is used for internal purposes only. It is not used in any way that would disclose personally identifiable information to outside parties unless System Administration is legally required to do so.
>>
>>> **b. Logs and Network Monitoring**
>>>
>>>> System Administration maintains log files of all access to its site and also monitors network traffic for the purposes of site management and security. This information is used to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative tasks. Log analysis tools are also used to create summary statistics to determine which information is of most interest to users, to identify system problem areas, or to help determine technical requirements.
>>>> 
>>>> The following information is collected in these files:
>>>>
>>>>> **Hostname:** the hostname, site name, username, and IP address of the computer requesting access to the site
>>>>> 
>>>>> **User-Agent:** the type of browser, its version, and the operating system of the computer requesting access (e.g., Netscape 4 for Windows, IE 4 for Macintosh, etc.)  
> 
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Referrer:** the web page the user came from 
>>>>> 
>>>>> **System date:** the date and time on the server at the time of access  
> 
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Full request:** the exact request the user made
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Status:** the status code the server returned, e.g., fulfilled request, file not found  
> 
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Content length** : the size, in bytes, of the file sent to the user
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Method:** the request method used by the browser (e.g., post, get)  
> 
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Universal Resource Identifier (URI):** the location of the particular resource requested. (More commonly known as a URL.)
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Query string of the URI:** anything after a question mark in a URI. For example, if a keyword search has been requested, the search word will appear in the query string.   
> 
>>>>> 
>>>>> **Protocol:** the technical protocol and version used, i.e., http 1.0, ftp, etc.   
>  The above information is not used in any way that would reveal personally identifying information to outside parties unless System Administration is legally required to do so. Web server logs are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with the rules and regulations of the Texas State Library and Archives Commission.
>> 
>> ### II. Information Collected by Email and Forms
>>
>>> U.T. System Administration collects the e-mail address of those individuals who communicate with us via e-mail or who give us their e-mail address. U.T. System Administration collects information that is voluntarily or automatically provided by those individuals who communicate with us via e-mail, who open and interact with our e-mails by, for example, following embedded links or who submit forms embedded in the e-mail or linked to our web site. 
>>> 
>>> If a member of the general public sends System Administration an e-mail message or fills out an e-mail or web-based form with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, that information will only be used for the purposes for which the form is intended, to respond to the question or comment, and to analyze trends. The message or form may be redirected to another government agency or person who is better able to respond to the question or comment. U.T. System Administration does not market such information. U. T. System Administration does not use such information in any way that would reveal personally identifying information to outside parties unless we are legally required to do so.  
> 
>> 
>> ### III. Notice About Information Laws and Practices  
> 
>>
>>> With few exceptions, you are entitled on your request to be informed about the information U.T. System Administration collects about you. Under Sections [552.021](http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/statutes/go/go0055200.html#go015.552.021) and [552.023](http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/statutes/go/go0055200.html#go017.552.023) of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to receive and review the information. Under Section 559.004 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to have U.T. System Administration correct information about you that is held by us and that is incorrect, in accordance with the procedures set forth in Business Procedures Memorandum 32.
>>> 
>>> The information that U.T. System Administration collects will be retained and maintained as required by Texas records retention laws ([Section 441.180](http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/statutes/go/go0044100.html#go083.441.180) et seq. of the Texas Government Code) and rules. Different types of information are kept for different periods of time.
>> 
>> ### IV. Links  
> 
>>
>>> This site contains links to other sites outside of System Administration. U.T. System Administration is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.
>> 
>> ### V. Security
> 
> This site has security measures in place to protect from loss, misuse and alteration of the information under the control of System Administration.   
> 
> 
> **Contacting System Administration**  
>  If there are any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or dealings with this web site, contact 
> 
> 
> * * *
> 
> * * *
